const ques = [
    {
        id: 1,
        question:"Recently, Facebook underwent a re branding and adopted this new identity",
        answer:"Meta",
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question:"In recent times, Facebook and Meta have engaged in a competitive rivalry within this industry.",
        answer:"Metaverse",
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question:"The universe of digital virtual reality, combining augmented reality and shared online experiences",
        answer:"Meta",
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question:"What term refers to 'universe' in a virtual context?(hint: think mark zuckerberg)",
        answer:"Metaverse",
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question:"'The Matrix' movie explores a simulated reality, often referred to as the __________(hint: think mark zuckerberg)",
        answer:"Metaverse",
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        question:"What kind of 'printer' can build tangible 3-D objects from digital designs?",
        answer:"3DPrinter",
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        question:"Cutting-edge technology that can create three-dimensional objects layer by layer",
        answer:"3DPrinter",
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        question:"What will you use to covert your 2-D designed objects to 3-d(hint:it's a printer)",
        answer:"3DPrinter",
    },
    {
        id:9,
        question:"Sci-fi weapon that emits a powerful beam of light (P.S. Tinkering Lab uses this technology for fibre cutting)",
        answer:"LASER",
    },
    {
        id: 10,
        question:"Technology used in medical procedures for precision cutting(P.S. Tinkering Lab uses this technology for fibre cutting)",
        answer:"LASER",
    },
    {
        id: 11,
        question:"In 'Star Wars', this weapon is a key part of blasters and lightsabers(P.S. Tinkering Lab uses this technology for fibre cutting)",
        answer:"LASER",
    },
    {
        id: 12,
        question:"This type of weapon is often used in sci-fi movies and video games (Hint: It stands for Light Amplification by Stimulated Emission of Radiation) (P.S. Tinkering Lab uses this technology for fibre cutting)",
        answer:"LASER",
    },
    {
        id: 13,
        question:"The 'father of the atomic bomb'",
        answer:"Oppenheimer",
    },
    {
        id: 14,
        question:"This scientist quoted this from Bhagwad Gita-'I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds'",
        answer:"Oppenheimer",
    },
    {
        id: 15,
        question:"Nolan's recently released movie is based on this scientist.",
        answer:"Oppenheimer",
    },
    {
        id: 16,
        question:"Surname of the person who is considered as the father of modern innovation",
        answer:"Edison",
    },
    {
        id: 17,
        question:"What is the name of the first commercial battery-powered car?",
        answer:"Tesla",
    },
    {
        id: 18,
        question:"Recently, Facebook underwent a re branding and adopted this new identity",
        answer:"Meta",
    },
    {
        id: 19,
        question:"What do you call an unmanned aircraft?",
        answer:"Drone",
    },
    {
        id: 20,
        question:"Which LLM model was recently developed by OpenAI, which initiated the new AI generation?",
        answer:"ChatGPT",
    },
    {
        id: 21,
        question:"What is the underlying technology of Bitcoin?",
        answer:"Blockchain",
    },
]

export default ques;